Timothy Merritt

MSc Strategic Innovation Management

Driven strategic innovator with 3.5 years of experience leading and managing innovation at operational and strategic levels. Specialised in project and programme management, creative problem solving and technology scouting. MSc in Strategic Innovation Management, University of Sussex. Looking to leverage strategic and analytical skills to drive innovation in both large and growing organisations.

Work Experience

Innovation Coordinator

2024-02present.

Digital Catapult | London Kings Cross

I currently accelerate 5G & quantum technologies in the UK capital.

I'm particularly interested in increasing knowledge flows & improving how insights are managed to enhance intrafirm capabilities to create a more future facing ecosystem.

2023-05.

HOC evidence paper on behalf of SPRU

House of Commons (HOC) select committee call for evidence | London Commercializing quantum technologies inquiry. I led, produced, and submitted a paper on how to improve the commercialization of quantum technologies in the UK to the House of Commons select committee, on behalf of the Science Policy Research Unit (SPRU).

Founder & CEO

2022-03-Present.

Trees for Graduates Ltd | Sussex

Partnering with local water companies, landowners and researchers aimed at improving the water quality of British head rivers by enhancing ecological life and slowing the flow.

 Work with Biology Professors and ecological researchers from the University of Sussex to gain metrics towards scaling to credibly work in regional ESG markets.

2022-10 **–** 2023-08.

Ecosystem Research Analyst

Adelantum | Berkshire

Adelantum is a consultancy company that specializes in the translation of early stage pharmaceuticals and scaling FMCGs.

- Supported client business strategy thorough mapping potential collaborators and competitors to navigate new product development strategies for a probiotic client.
- Market analysis for various FMCG clients.

2021-07 -2022-10

Healthcare innovation

University Hospital Sussex | Sussex

Delivered various innovative plays for the local Hospital Charity. The Charity went through a merger with seven surrounding charities at the time. advised on branding, gathered insights and wrote proposals for migrant nurse housing, aswell as creating digital fundraising revenue streams including a gaming for good initiative.

Contact

Address

Berkshire

F-mail

Merritt.st@gmail.com

Skills

- Microsoft Office tools (PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Project)
- Systems thinking
- Creative problem solving
- Innovation Management
- Strategy & consultancy

Languages

- English (fluent)
- Spanish (basic)

Interests

Entrepreneurship, reading - mainly innovation management literature, endurance and combat sports.

- 2022-23 Sussex University Fencing society President.
- British Academy of Management volunteer 2023.

2020-05 - Blood science associate

Royal Berkshire | Reading

Worked in A&E in my hometown operating and researching PCR machines to support my community. Gathering data and interoperability insights for DWR (Diagnostics for the real world) SAMBA 11 PCR machines:

 Management: Oversaw the point of care testing for blood gas machines in A&E and held regular systems reports with PCR engineers as hard and soft systems were being scaled in real time.

Education

2021-09 - Master of Science: Strategic Innovation Management 2023-09

The University of Sussex | Brighton

Predicted grade: Distinction. The master's is focused on leading and managing innovation at operational and strategic levels. Modules included: Industrial & innovation policy, AI policy, Digital Transformation, Network Analysis and Infographics, Innovation Management, product management, Intellectual Property Management, Science, technology and Innovation.

2022-10 - Innovation: incubator programme

Sussex innovation center | Sussex

A one-year course covering: Entrepreneurship Masterclasses and mentorship sessions with nation leading experts in data science, sales, management and finance

2022-07 - Summer School: Accelerator programme

2022-10

Sussex enterprise | Sussex

A 12-week course covering: Entrepreneurial and Corporative Strategy, Strategic Responses to Crisis, Sustainable Strategy and Consulting.

2013-09 - Bachelor of Arts Honors: Fine Art

2018-07

Newcastle University | Newcastle

Degree in Fine Art with special interests in conceptual Art and history. Newcastle University department ranked $1^{\rm st}$ in the UK for Fine Art.

Accomplishments & Awards

2022-11 Sussex Elevate Grant 2022

Through a Santander & Sussex University collaboration fund, Trees for Graduates had research and pilot studies funded. As a result, the Dean mentioned us in every Graduation speech in 2023, encouraging full Graduate & family participation.

2022-03 Pitch for the Planet 2022, University of Sussex

Awarded 1st place for the Pitch for the Planet, Sustainability Competition with $\pounds 5,000$ prize to implement the project 'Trees for Graduates'.

Fine Art scholar, The Oratory school

2007-13 Awarded a Fine Art scholarship for creativity and artistic ability at the highest-ranking school for excellence in Fine Art school in the UK.

References David Eggleton Paul Nightingale